Undeclared wars are commonplace.
Tragically, our government engages in
preemptive war, otherwise known as
aggression, with no complaints from the
American people. [music] Sadly, we have
become accustomed to living with the
illegitimate use of force by government.
To develop a truly free society, the
issue of initiating force [music] must
be understood
and rejected.
What if sometimes to love your country,
you [music] had to alter or abolish the
government? What if Jefferson was right?
What if that [music] government is best
which governs least?
What if it is dangerous to be right when
the government [music] is wrong?
What if it is better to perish fighting
for freedom than to live as a slave?
[music]
What if freedom's greatest hour of
danger
is now?
>> [music]
>> Hi everyone, Judge Andrew Napolitano
here for Judging Freedom. Today is
Monday, March 2nd, 2026. John Kiriakou
will be with us in just a moment on Iran
and the CIA. What has been the CIA's
involvement in bringing us to this war?
But first, this.
>> [music]
>> Don't you just cringe when people say,
"I told you so"? Sorry, I told you gold
and silver would reap the benefits due
to excessive money printing, inflation,
and global uncertainty. It's here. It's
happened. Gold and silver reached
all-time [music] highs. Did you call
Lear Capital and buy some? It's not too
late. Experts [music] are predicting
higher prices ahead. Why? Nothing has
changed. Geopolitical chaos, cost of
[music] living crises, and a weaker
dollar are driving central banks to
boost their gold reserves. Forecast
suggests gold could hit $6,000 an ounce
and silver $200 an ounce. [music] Even
Morgan Stanley ditched the 60/40 rule
for 60/20/20,
putting 20% into precious metals.
They're getting educated [music] and you
should, too. Call the best in the
business and the people I trust, Lear
Capital. [music]
Get their reports, get the facts, get
some gold and silver. Tell [music] them
the judge sent you and get up to $20,000
in bonus gold or silver. [music] Call
800-511-4620
or go to Learjudgenap.com.
John Kiriakou, my dear friend, a
pleasure. Thank you very much for
>> is mine. uh joining us today. Before we
get to your uh understanding of the role
of Intel in this war, what is your view,
big picture, of this uh congressionally
undeclared
war of choice that Donald Trump started
on Friday night? Oh, I'm utterly utterly
opposed for a number of reasons. First
of all, it's congressionally undeclared.
The Constitution is very clear. There
should be a congressional declaration of
war, and that hasn't happened. Not only
has that not happened, Congress hasn't
even been briefed. And so, our elected
officials have no idea what the policy
is.
Is is the president telling us the truth
when he says that that this is going to
last a few weeks?
Because later in the afternoon today, he
said that this could go on for for
months.
And what's the goal? It's easy to start
a war, it's easy to overthrow a
government, it's very very difficult to
stabilize a region and then pull out
safely. Did we learn nothing in Iraq or
Afghanistan?
So, I'm I'm gravely concerned about this
whole thing.
Uh there are reports
uh in European media today. I haven't
seen any of them over here
that over the weekend the Trump
administration reached out to the
Italian foreign ministry
and asked them to reach out to the
Iranian foreign industry
foreign ministry, excuse me, uh and
offer a ceasefire. If true, what does
that tell you about the American
thinking if they want a ceasefire 48
hours after they started?
That tells me that they thought the
entire Iranian government would collapse
as soon as hostilities were initiated.
That hasn't happened and they're
starting to worry about a plan B. Also,
I learned just in the last couple of
hours that the United Arab Emirates has
seven days worth of surface-to-air
missiles left and Qatar has four days
worth of surface-to-air missiles left.
Both countries have reached out urgently
to the United States asking for
replacements and there are no
replacements.
So something's got to give.
These are countries
that
house American military personnel and
Iran is not attacking civilians or even
government in those countries. It's
attacking the American bases. Do I have
that right?
For the most part, there have been a
couple of Iranian suicide drones
uh
aimed at the Burj Khalifa, the the
tallest building in the world, that's in
Dubai, at the Jebel Ali free port just
south of Dubai, and then oddly at the
port of Oman and a small town outside of
Muscat. I'm not sure exactly what what
the reason for that would be, especially
because it was the Omanis who were
trying to negotiate a deal between the
US and Iran. But for the most part, the
Iranian targets are American military
installations. Yes, in specifically the
GCC countries, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait,
Bahrain, Qatar, Oman, and the United
Arab Emirates. Uh we know of 18
casualties, among whom are four
uh four fatalities.
Uh I don't know the status of the three
American pilots whose jet planes were
shot down supposedly by mistake by the
Kuwaitis. I believe that they bailed out
and landed uh safely. If they landed in
Kuwait, they're probably safe by now. I
mean, Kuwait is not going to
>> That's the report.
>> harm them or uh or detain them. Right.
You heard from
uh uh publicly from President Trump or
Secretary of State Pompeo or Secretary
of State Hagseth
for a clear delineation of the goal of
this war or a clear articulation of a
feasible military goal?
I have not, Your Honor. And I'll tell
you this reminds me very, very much of
the run-up to war with Iraq in 2002 and
early 2003, where all anybody in the
policy community wanted to talk about
was initiating hostilities, and there
was no plan to get out. There was no
plan to try to encourage a stable uh
popular government. It was just move in,
overthrow, and see what happens next.
And it's like history repeating itself.
What What What does the CIA have to do,
if anything, with the initiation of
these hostilities? For example,
on Friday
uh when this war started, I guess it was
Friday evening uh Iran time, or maybe it
was Saturday morning uh Iran time, I
think.
Were there CIA agents on the ground in
Tehran?
You know, 24 hours ago I would have said
that's ridiculous,
but it's actually not ridiculous. The
New York Times reported that the truth
of what happened on the ground is the
opposite of what we were led to believe.
We were led to believe that the Mossad
had the Iranian government utterly
infiltrated from the top to the bottom.
But the New York Times reported
yesterday that it was actually the CIA
that had the Iranian government
infiltrated and it was the CIA that
passed locational targeting information
on the Iranian leadership to the
Israelis that the Israelis then used to
kill Supreme Leader Khamenei and
former President Ahmadinejad and
virtually the entire military and
nuclear leadership. It was a CIA
operation, not a Mossad operation. How
did the CIA know
uh that the Ayatollah and his family
were in his house at one time in one
place?
Well, I think they knew a couple of
different ways. First of all, Ayatollah
Khamenei was actually pretty public
with a statement that if the Iranian
people didn't have bunkers to run to
that he would not run to a bunker.
And so it was pretty likely that he was
going to be either in his house or his
office, which were both in the same
compound.
I don't think anybody could have guessed
that his family would be there. I I
would have assumed his family had run,
you know, into hiding, but when the
Israelis bombed the compound, they
killed everybody and it turned out to be
Khamenei, his daughter, his son-in-law,
and a grandchild. Um
you know, you have to wonder the
Israelis have bragged for years about
the number of people that they've
recruited in in Iran. And most of them,
at least many of them, were Afghan
refugees.
Refugees in Iran get nothing. They get
no food, no shelter, no medical care, no
nothing. And so if you approach these
people and you say, "Look, I'll give you
$100 a month to stand on this corner and
write in a little book how often General
so-and-so leaves his apartment and what
time and what time he returns and what
route he took when he left,
well, that's $100 you didn't have
yesterday. That's $100 that you can use
to feed yourself if you're a penniless
refugee.
And I think now that it wasn't just the
Israelis that had these operations
underway, it was also the CIA.
You know, when I was at the at the CIA,
it was virtually impossible to recruit
an Iranian. Um, but the CIA was trying
to recruit those people at the top,
somebody in the the Ayatollah's office
or the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the
Ministry of Defense, the IRGC.
Maybe they learned a lesson that you
should start at the bottom and collect
the information from the bottom and use
it for targeting because that's
apparently what they did over the last 3
days.
How do you explain the Israeli passion
for assassinations?
Yeah, it's it's pretty incredible, isn't
it?
Going back to the 50s,
the Israelis were very happy to
assassinate anybody that they deemed to
be a potential threat to the stability
of the State of Israel. And you know,
after the '72 Munich Olympic
massacre, it took them years
to track down, hunt down every single
Palestinian terrorist who was involved
in that operation and kill them one at a
time. Well, they've continued to do that
and the uh
>> [cough]
>> Excuse me. The Iranian milli or sorry,
the Iranian nuclear program
was rather easy for them to target
because many of those scientists would
travel overseas for seminars, academic
seminars. And the Israelis would knock
on the hotel door,
say, "We're with Mossad. You're going to
either work for us or you're going to
die."
And I'm going to assume some
said, "Okay, I'll take the deal." But
most others died. They're very happy.
And another thing with the Israelis,
too, they don't have a bureaucracy that
the United States has. You don't There's
no gang of four, gang of eight that you
have to um inform. There's no executive
order 12333.
You just do it. You want to kill
somebody? You just go out and kill them.
You uh mentioned one of Ronald Reagan's
greatest mistakes. I don't want to
deviate too much. 12333
which the uh intelligence community has
interpreted as forget about the Fourth
Amendment. Just spy on everybody, take
down whatever they say from whatever
source they have. And even Donald Trump
who was himself victimized by that
mentality and that uh executive order
uh has failed has failed to
uh to change it. How vulnerable
uh is Israel
to uh a continuous pounding by the
Iranians? I mean, last time around at
the 12-day war, we understand Prime
Minister Netanyahu begged the president
to call everything off so the Iranians
would stop uh attacking Israel.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, this is going to be a problem for
the Israelis. Uh the Israelis, I think,
were the ones who actually convinced the
Americans that as soon as the first
strikes began the Iranian government
would collapse and it hasn't collapsed.
And so I think the Israelis today are
saying, "Oh, no. What have we gotten
ourselves into?" Another problem that
the Israelis are are having and we've
already begun seeing it.
Here in the United States only 27% of
Americans, according to the latest
polls, support this this conflict. In
Europe it's even worse and for the very
first time here in the United States
since polls began being taken on this
issue, more people support the
Palestinians than support the Israelis.
Couple that with the unpopularity of
this attack and you've turned global
public opinion against yourself. Right.
So maybe it would have been a better
idea to negotiate in good faith rather
than to just pretend to negotiate, drag
it out as long as you can, tell the
Iranians that they have 10 more days to
make concessions and then just hit them
on day two. Yeah.
I mean who would negotiate with the
United States again after this? This is
the second time in eight months that uh
they figuratively speaking killed the
negotiators. They attacked the country
with which they were negotiating as the
negotiators were literally on their way
to the next session. And may I add
something as well?
You know, we're not talking about North
Korea today and there's a reason why
we're not talking about North Korea
because North Korea has a nuclear
weapon.
And so nobody wants to mess with North
Korea.
Well, the Iranians
weren't building a nuclear weapon. There
are two CIA national intelligence
estimates that concluded that there was
no nuclear weapons program besides the
fact that Ayatollah Khamenei issued a
fatwa decades ago
saying there will be no nuclear weapons
program.
But Benjamin Netanyahu came to the
United States dozens upon dozens of
times
to try to convince whoever happened to
be president at the time and we're going
back four or five presidents that Iran
was an existential threat and that there
was indeed a nuclear program and so Iran
had to be destroyed.
Well, that was a lie.
And now here we are in a hot war
wondering how we're going to get out of
it.
Here is our friend and colleague uh
Larry Johnson on this show
this morning on A, the absurdity of
killing the Ayatollah and B, the number
of Iranians
killed by the US government. Chris,
number 23. The one man that had blocked
that was the the the the spiritual
uh and actually political force keeping
Iran from going ahead with a nuke
uh was uh Khamenei. We killed him.
Now that he's out uh I cannot dismiss
the possibility that his replacement
will come in and say, "Look
uh for the benefit of protecting the
Iranian people
for to protect like these little girls,
there's 150 little girls, six you know,
between the ages of six and 12
that were murdered by the United States.
We got blood on our hands. That's why
they call death to America.
Because we are responsible for a minimum
of 300,000 dead Iranians over the course
of the last 46 years.
Make sense to you? Yeah, Larry's
correct. Larry's correct. There was no
nuclear weapons program. And you know,
killing Ayatollah Khamenei is like
killing the Pope. You're not going to
bring down Catholicism by killing the
Pope. There's just going to be another
Pope appointed. And it's the same
situation in Iran. There's going to be
another Grand Ayatollah or Ayatollah
elevated to Grand Ayatollah to supreme
leader. It very well could be the
Ayatollah Khomeini's grandson who is one
of the senior clerics and and an insider
and who's far far more conservative than
Ayatollah Khamenei was.
So, we've we've opened up a Pandora's
Box here and I'm not sure that there's a
way to close the lid.
Yeah.
Um
should Tulsi Gabbard stay in her job?
I mean, they obviously don't listen to
what she says. She testifies under oath
about these CIA assessments.
Uh when she testifies, she's got all the
written material in front of her in case
the members of Congress want to see it.
And Trump just dismisses it and says, "I
don't care what she says." Mhm. What he
means is what he means is
Netanyahu doesn't want to hear this.
That's really exactly what it means. And
if there [clears throat] is an
assessment published that he doesn't
like or approve of, he'll fire everybody
that was involved in the assessment. One
thing about the CIA and I I was taught
this in my very first week. The CIA does
not have the protections of the
the Civil Service Act. The CIA CIA
employees serve at the pleasure of the
president. And so, if the president
doesn't like your face or doesn't like
the tie that you're wearing or doesn't
like what you wrote in the president's
daily brief, he can fire you and there's
literally nothing you can do about it.
And
officers and analysts know this.
Oh, yes.
Yes. But, the thing is
every other president since the creation
of the CIA has wanted unbiased analysis.
The the No other president has wanted uh
a rubber stamp of his own policies,
whatever they happen to be. You know, I
remember as as a young man, I was still
in my 20s, 28 years old, and getting
into a written argument with Bill
Clinton over
uh the Iraqi no-fly zones.
And then finally, his briefer said, "You
know what? The president just gave up.
He admits you're the the expert. He's
not. He's going to go with your
analysis."
Well, that's
what what happened in normal situation.
Not that everybody's fired, and then you
just do what you want to do anyway.
Hm, where do you see this ending, John?
I don't think this is going to take
weeks, and I don't think we'll bring
down the Iranian government. One of the
things that I noticed, one of the things
that I rued the last couple of days, was
watching CNN, Fox, MSNBC, or MS Now it's
called, and these repeated references to
this tiny demonstration in Los Angeles
between 200 and 300 people jumping up
and down and dancing and singing and and
applauding the uh the attack.
Well, these are
mostly Iranian Jews, most of whom
settled in Southern California. Um many
of them in Beverly Hills. These were
pro-Shah people who fled in 1979,
took their wealth with them. That's not
the average Iranian.
You know, there are demonstrations in
Tehran
um that are pro-government, that have
had hundreds of thousands of people.
And so, I think we've grossly
underestimated the support, the domestic
support, that this uh Iranian government
has. And I think that we will not see a
quick collapse. Wouldn't the murder
of the Ayatollah reinforce that support?
Absolutely. You know, this was something
that we miscalculated at the start of
the Iran war. I remember being in a I
was the note-taker in a principal's
committee meeting the night before we
attacked Iraq. And one of the National
Security Council's senior advisers, as
we got up to walk out of the room, said,
"When we cross that border tomorrow,
they're going to throw flowers at us."
And I went back to the office and I said
to the Deputy Director of the CIA, "Do
these people know nothing about
history?"
And he said, "No.
They know nothing about history. And
here we are repeating that same mistake
that we made 24 years ago."
John Kiriakou, thank you, my dear
friend. A pleasure
pleasure to interview you. I hope we can
see you at the end of the week. Thank
you so much. I look forward to that.
Good to see you. Thank you. All the
best. Coming up tomorrow, Tuesday, at
8:00 in the morning, Ambassador Chas
Freeman.
At 9:00 in the morning, Professor John
Mearsheimer. At 10:00 in the morning,
Aaron Maté. At 12:45
in the afternoon, Scott Ritter. At 2:00,
Matt Hoh. These are full days. At 3:00,
Colonel Karen Kwiatkowski. Thank you for
watching Judge Napolitano for Judging
Freedom.
>> [music]
[music]